

Alberto Hurtado Ruiz

Nationality: Spanish | Email address: alberto.hurt.99@gmail.com |

Address: Madrid, Spain (Home)

ABOUT ME

I am a backend developer specialized in Scala using Akka, and Kafka. I have worked with relational and non relational database systems lilke MongoDB and Postgres.

I am passionate about quality software craftmanship following good practices and agile methodologies.

My programming languages of preference are: Scala, Java, Typescript and Python.

I have experience working with the following frameworks and libraries: Spark, Play, Akka, Spring.

I have experience with AWS and Azure.

Language skills:

Spanish: nativeEnglish: C2German: B1

WORK EXPERIENCE

20/11/2023 - CURRENT

BACKEND AND BIG DATA DEVELOPER AXPE CONSULTING

Be involved in the whole software development lifecycle for the privacy platform of Telefónica global focusing on REST services and big data.

This includes designing solutions, implementing them and testing them. Also give support to hotfixes in preproduction environments.

Technologies used: Scala, Spark, Posgres, Kubernetes, Elasticsearch

19/07/2021 - 17/11/2023 Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ENGINEER ALTEN DELIVERY CENTER

(Inditex client) 25/09/2023 - 17/11/2023

- Contributed to the Inditex open platform project, aimed at centralizing legacy applications into a single platform.
- Introduced good practices and standardized processes within the team.
- Collaborated with the Team Lead and development team to implement hexagonal architecture in the new project.
- Designed APIs to meet frontend data requirements based on functional specifications provided by Product Owners.

(Macq client) 19/07/2021 - 25/09/2023

- Served as a backend developer consultant for an international smart mobility project within an agile team setup.
- Collaborated closely with the Product Owner, Functional Analyst, and other development teams in feature design.
- Played a pivotal role in the delivery and maintenance of microservices for a high-volume, real-time web application.
- Prioritized achieving high performance, ensuring code maintainability, and comprehensive test coverage.

07/02/2021 - 19/06/2021 Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN IF INTELLIGENT FULFILLMENT

- Collaborated with the development team of a startup.
 - Assisted the senior developer in:

- Designing the data model and architecture.
- Implementing business logic.
- Ensuring timely deliveries for main e-commerce platforms.

07/07/2020 - 31/12/2020 Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AMAZON BUSINESS

- Developed an automation solution to streamline manual tasks for on-call ticket resolutions.
- Utilized various AWS services, including EC2, CloudWatch, Lambdas, API Gateway, IAM, and SNS topics.
- Implemented infrastructure as code for comprehensive project configuration.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

09/09/2017 - 21/07/2021 Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE ENGINEER E.T.S.I.S.I Universidad Politécnica de Madrid

Website https://www.etsisi.upm.es/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **SPANISH**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
GERMAN	B1	B1	B1	B1	B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user